# ERICK LUMUNGE

Nairobi, Kenya

lumungep12@gmail.com

https://ke.linkedin.com/in/lumunge

https://github.com/lumunge



Programming Languages: C++, Typescript, Python, Solidity, Java, Shell



#### PROFILE SUMMARY

Lumunge is a passionate software developer with 2.5 years of professional software development experience designing and developing scalable, performant and maintainable web applications.

| - 7    | 0     |
|--------|-------|
| $\sim$ |       |
| $\sim$ | F=Y   |
| -11    | ĺ     |
| ¬11    | ĺ     |
| "      | =,    |
| CS1°   |       |
| $\sim$ | I A . |

#### SKILLS

Agile Development Data structures Algorithm design Reliability

**Problem Solving** Adaptability

SQL/NoSQL/PostgreSQL Time Management

Cryptography and Encryption Interpersonal Skills

Blockchain/NFTs/DeFi/ Web3/Hyperledger

**Technical Writing** 



#### TOOLS & TECHNOLOGIES

Redux React.js **Eclipse** Next.js Truffle **VSCode** 

Node.is Ganache Git/Github/GitLab

**Brownie** Redis Linux Docker Ether.js **GIMP** 

Django



#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## **Opengenus IQ: Software Developer**

Nov, 2021 - Present

- Worked with stakeholder to implement new features.
- Continually debugged and optimized the code.
- Worked with stakeholder to specify project requirements
- Created over 500 articles on various computer science and software development topics.
- Developed a data structures project for visualizing graph algorithms and algorithmic problems.

#### Freelance Developer

April, 2021 - Nov, 2021

- Continually identified, advised and delivered scalable solutions.
- Worked with clients to plan requirements.
- Increased business sales and market outreach by creating an online store.
- Offered outstanding service to my clients.
- Drove excellence through optimized and maintainable code.



#### **PROJECTS**

Jamii Blockchain Voting

An e-voting system that leverages the benefits of a public blockchain.(HTML, CSS, Material UI, Next.js, Solidity, Python

**Graph algorithms Visualization** 

A visualization of common graph algorithms and algorithmic problems involving graph theory. (Typescript, Javascript, CSS, HTML)

**Arbitrage CLI Tool** 

A CLI tool that scrapes data from multiple websites to find arbitrage opportunities. (Python, SQL, Shell)



### EDUCATION

#### Coursera Specialization Courses.

2020 - 2021

Mathematical Thinking in Computer Science

Data structures and Algorithms.

#### **Kenya Methodist University**

2018 - 2019

Diploma in Computer Information Systems.